

Poorya Sheikh

Cloud DevOps Engineer

poorya.sheikh@gmail.com

+77478086640

Almaty, Kazakhstan

linkedin.com/in/poorya-sheikh

github.com/pooryasheikh

Experienced Cloud DevOps Engineer with 5 years combined as Cloud, and DevOps engineer, as well as Linux Systems Administrator. Solid understanding of principles of Continuous Integration, Continuous Deployment, Continuous Delivery, and Cloud Implementations with demonstrated hands-on field experience. In-depth experience in AWS cloud services such as EKS, EC2, S3, EBS, ELB, Cloud Watch, Elastic IP, RDS, IAM, VPC, and Route53.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Cloud Providers AWS, Linode, Digital Ocean, Hetzner **Databases** MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, ScyllaDB

laC **Key DBs** Redis, MemcacheD Terraform, SaltStack, Ansible, Terragrunt

Virtualization Proxmox, Ovirt **Load balancers** Nginx, HAproxy, Metallb, Proxysql

Message brokers RabbitMQ, Kafka Loa Graylog, Loki, Datadog, ELK

Managements

Service Mesh: Istio, Linkerd, Envoy, Consul **Programming** Python, Shell, Lua

Container Kubernetes, Docker Swarm Monitoring Sentry, Datadog, Elastic APM, Zabbix,

Orchestrations Datadog, Grafana, Prometheus

WORK EXPERIENCES

Cloud DevOps Engineer

Evrone Team 02/2022 - Present

Evrone.com is an IT consultant Company specializing in the development of services for high-load systems.

Achievements/Tasks

- Improved Helm chart from simple chart to umbrella chart for better version controlling between the company branches.
- Implemented FluxCD to change from push base deployment to pull base for improve continuous delivery.
- Administered CloudFlare with +6 domain for proxies DNS record to Kubernetes Nginx Ingress Controller.
- Initiated infrastructure as a code with combination of Terraform and Terragrunt for AWS cloud services such as EKS, S3, EC2, RDS, VPC, and etc.
- Migrated from private cloud provider to AWS for better managing the budget and high availability of the system.

DevOps Engineer

Arbuz Team

04/2021 - 02/2022 Almaty, Kazakhstan

Arbuz is an online supermarket which has quickly become the largest one in the country, and the favorite choice of many.

- Achievements/Tasks
- Designed an architectural diagram for applications before migrating into Public Cloud (OpenStack PS.kz) for flexible, costeffective, reliable, scalable, high-performance and secured operations.
- Designed and built a continuous integration and deployment with Helm chart in Gitlab.
- Deployed VPC with full-mesh tunnel between cloud providers.
- Migrated from Docker Swarm to Kubernetes for better handling over deployment and container horizontal auto scaling.
- Implemented Single Source of Truth as an authentication center based on FreeIPA for all internal authentication (SSH, LDAP integration, and Policy management).

Remote

WORK EXPERIENCES

System Administrator

Kolesa Group

08/2019 - 04/2021 Almaty, Kazakhstan

Services for the placement and publication of private ads for the sale and purchase of cars, real estate, and services in Kazakhstan.

- Achievements/Tasks
- Administered more than 2500 virtual machine in Proxmox clusters in 5 data centers.
- Implemented AWX in Kubernetes, and lifted all the playbooks to the AWX.
- Used Ansible and AWX as Configuration management tools, to automate repetitive tasks, quickly deploys critical
 applications, and proactively manages change.
- Developed dynamic inventory in python for Ansible to interact with API of FreeIPAM.
- Launched intrusion detection system base on Suricata for monitoring ingress and egress traffic in every data center (multi zone).

System Administrator

RG Brands

04/2018 - 07/2019 Almaty, Kazakhstan

RG brands is a leading beverage company.

- Achievements/Tasks
- Converted ATC to VoIP for more than 500 extensions
- Designed super mesh networking of the main branch building with 25 access switches, 2 core switches, and a core router
- Administered more than 100 servers physical and virtual
- Managed Microsoft Active Directory for more than 600 users and computers
- Implemented monitoring system with Zabbix and Grafana
- Built clusters of OVirt with GlusterFS storage system

EDUCATION

Associate Degree in Information and Communication Technology
 Jahad University of Ahvaz

2009 - 2012

LANGUAGES

English Russian Persian

Professional Working Proficiency Professional Working Proficiency Native or Bilingual Proficiency